Scott Fowler



KEY QUALIFICATIONS

UX/UI DESIGN & FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT

Front-end Web Development: UX/UI Design / HTML, CSS with Sass, JavaScript / Bootstrap Framework **Front-end build tools:** gulp.js, node.js, npm / **Frameworks:** Razor in .ASP.Net MVC / Familiar with Agile workflow / Basic database gueries

UX/UI DESIGN & FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT SKILLS

HTML - 10+ years

CSS - 9 years

JavaScript - 6 years

Bootstrap - 4+ years

UX Design - 5+ years

Wireframing - 5+ years

Sketch with InVision for mockups

Git Source Control/TFS Source Control

Agile Processes

Adobe CC Suite

Visual Studio/Visual Studio Code

Atlassian BitBucket, Jira, Confluence

ASP.Net MVC

EDUCATION

2015 -2014

DIPLOMA - WEB DESIGN

Art Institute of Pittsburgh Pittsburgh, PA

CLASSES: Fundamentals of the Internet, Design Fundamentals, Image Manipulation, Digital Color Theory, Applications & Industry, Typography-Traditional, User-Centered Information Design, Screen Design & Graphics, Interactive Authoring, Basic Web Scripting, Web Site Development, Intro to Programming, Database Systems, Web Site Development II, Sophomore Digital Portfolio.

1995 -1993

ASSOCIATES OF APPLIED STUDIES - ADVERTISING ART

Art Center Design College Albuquerque, NM

GRAPHIC DESIGN: Knowledge of 1-4 color designs, advertisements, newsletters, brochures, multi-media campaigns, posters, books and manuals.

ILLUSTRATION: Knowledge of 1-4 color designs, advertisements, newsletters, brochures, multi-media campaigns, posters, books and manuals.

PRINT PRODUCTION:

- Familiar with 4 color CMYK printing, spot and b&w production, including glossy work.
- · Meet multiple deadlines on a daily basis.

Scott Fowler



EXPERIENCE

Present -2016

DESIGNER & FRONT-END DEVELOPER

New Mexico Interactive Santa Fe. NM

Designer/Front-end Developer providing UI/UX website designs to corporate developers and designing business collateral for company and customers. Maintain database upkeep through Raven Database.

2015 -2013

CREATIVE SERVICES MANAGER

Albuquerque Publishing Company Albuquerque, NM

Managed Art Department newspaper staff of 8 graphic designers, while providing creative guidance, direction, and solutions for advertisers.

- · Improved and optimized company processes for graphic design, web design.
- · Developed a comprehensive user experience process for the company in regards to web site development.
- Initiated digital processes for the company by creating web advertisements, landing pages, and companion web sites.

2000 -2013

MULTIMEDIA DESIGNER / ART DEPARTMENT MANAGER PRODUCTION COORDINATOR / GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Santa Fe New Mexican Santa Fe. NM

Managed Art Department newspaper staff of 5 graphic designers. Directed general graphic design, web design & development, marketing & print production processes.

- · Collaborated with company web team to successfully implement new content management system, TownNews.
- Successfully instituted ad positions within the content management system and directed the online advertising management system.
- Developed the marketing campaign concept for over 50 different advertisements in one of the most successful and versatile marketing campaigns the company ever used, You Turn to Us.
- Established graphics, procedures, templates, and workflow for the development of Photoshop & Flash web advertisements.
- Designed & developed the first company companion websites, including the advertising rates and pet calendar websites, marketing email blasts, and company online newsletters.
- · Designed and created advertisements for print products.